Most of the supervised learning algorithms
在大多数我们已经学到的（字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，黄海广，haiguang2000@qq.com）
we've seen, things like linear
监督学习算法中，类似于线性回归
regression, logistic regression and
逻辑回归，以及更多的算法
so on. All of those
所有的这些
algorithms have an optimization objective
算法都有一个优化目标函数
or some cost function that the algorithm was trying to minimize.
或者某个代价函数需要通过算法进行最小化
It turns out that K-means also
事实上 K均值也有
has an optimization objective or
一个优化目标函数或者
a cost function that is trying to minimize.
需要最小化的代价函数
And in this video, I'd like to tell
在这个视频中 我会
you what that optimization objective is.
告诉大家这个优化目标函数是什么
And the reason I want to do so
我这么做有两方面的目的
is because this will be useful to us for two purposes.
具体来说
First, knowing what is the
首先 了解什么是
optimization objective of K-means
K均值的优化目标函数
will help us to
这将能帮助我们
debug the learning algorithm and
调试学习算法
just make sure that K-means is
确保K均值算法
running correctly, and second,
是在正确运行中
and perhaps even more importantly, in
第二个也是最重要的一个目的是
a later video we'll talk
在之后的视频中我们将讨论
about how we can use this to
我们该怎样运用这个来
help K-means find better clusters
帮助K均值找到更好的簇
and avoid local optima, but we'll do that in a later video that follows this one.
并且避免局部最优解，不过我们在这节课之后的视频中才会涉及到
Just as a quick reminder, while K-means is
另外顺便提一下 当K均值正在运行时
running we're going to be
我们将
keeping track of two sets of variables.
对两组变量进行跟踪
First is the CI's and
首先是 c(i)
that keeps track of the
它表示的是
index or the number of the cluster
当前的样本 x(i) 所归为
to which an example x(i) is currently assigned.
的那个簇的索引或者序号
And then, the other set of variables
另外一组变量
we use as Mu subscript
我们用 μk 来表示
K, which is the location
第 k 个簇的
of cluster centroid K. And,
聚类中心 (cluster centroid)
again, for K-means
顺便再提一句
we use capital K to denote the total number of clusters.
K均值中我们用大写 K
And here lower case K,
来表示簇的总数
you know, is going to be an
用小写 k 来表示
index into the cluster
聚类中心的序号
centroids, and so lower
因此
case k is going to be
小写 k 的范围
a number between 1 and
就应该是1到大写K之间
capital K. Now, here's
除此以外
one more bit of notation which
还有另一个符号
is going to use Mu
我们用 μc(i)
subscript c(i) to denote
来表示
the cluster centroid of the
x(i) 所属的那个簇
cluster to which example x(i)
的聚类中心
has been assigned and
我再稍微多解释一下
to explain that notation
这个符号
a little bit more, let's
假如说
say that x(i) has been
x(i) 被划为了
assigned to cluster number five.
第5个簇
What that means is that c(i),
这是什么意思呢？
that is the index of x(i),
这个意思是 x(i) 的序号
that that is equal to 5.
也就是 c(i) 等于5
Right? Because you know, having c(i) equals 5,
因为 c(i) = 5
that's what it means for the
表示的就是
example x(i) to be
x(i) 这个样本
assigned to cluster number 5.
被分到了第五个簇
And so Mu subscript
因此
c(i) is going to
μ 下标 c(i)
be equal to Mu subscript
就等于  μ5
5 because c(i) is equal
因为 c(i) 就是5
to 5.
所以
This Mu substitute c(i) is the
这里的 μc(i)
cluster centroid of cluster number
就是第5个簇的聚类中心
5, which is the cluster
而也正是我的样本 x(i)
to which my example x(i) has been assigned.
所属的第5个簇
With this notation, we're now
有了这样的符号表示
ready to write out what
现在我们就能写出
is the optimization objective of
K均值聚类算法的
the K Mu clustering algorithm.
优化目标了
And here it is.
以下便是
The cost function that K-means
K均值算法需要
is minimizing is the
最小化的代价函数
function J of all of
J 参数是 c(1) 到 c(m)
these parameters c1 through
以及 μ1 到 μk
cM, Mu1 through MuK, that
随着算法的执行过程
K-means is varying as the algorithm runs.
这些参数将不断变化
And the optimization objective is shown
右边给出了优化目标
on the right, is the average of
也就是所有的
one over M of the sum
1/m 乘以
of i equals one through M of this term here
i = 1 到 m 个项的求和
that I've just drawn the red box around.
这里我用红色框出了这部分
The squared distance between
也即每个样本 x(i)
each example x(i) and the
到 x(i) 所属的
location of the cluster
聚类簇的中心
centroid to which x(i)
距离的平方值
has been assigned.
被分配
So let me just draw this in, let me explain this.
我来解释一下
Here is the location of training
这是训练样本 x(i) 的位置
example x(i), and here's the location
这是 x(i) 这个样本被划分到的
of the cluster centroid to which
聚类簇的中心的位置
example x(i) has been assigned.
我们在图上解释一下
So to explain this in pictures, if here is X1, X2.
如果这是 x1 x2
And if a point
并且如果这个点
here, is my example
是我的第 i 个样本
x(i), so if that
x(i) 那么
is equal to my example x(i),
也就是说这个值等于 x(i)
and if x(i) has been assigned
并且 x(i) 被分到了
to some cluster centroid, and
某一个聚类中心
I'll denote my cluster centroid with a cross.
我用一个叉来表示这个聚类中心
So if that's the location of,
所以 如果我们假设
you know, Mu 5, let's
这个聚类中心是 μ5
say, if x(i) has been
也就是说 假如 x(i)
assigned to cluster centroid 5 in my example up there.
被分到第五个聚类簇
Then, the squared distance, that's
那么这个距离平方值
the squared of the distance
也就是点 x(i)
between the point x(i) and this
和 x(i) 被分配到的聚类中心的
cluster centroid, to which x(i) has been assigned.
距离的平方值
And what K-means can be shown
那么 K均值算法
to be doing is that, it
要做的事情就是
is trying to find parameters c(i)
它将找到参数 c(i) 和 μi
and Mu(i), try to
并且
find cMU to try to
找到能够最小化
minimize this cost function J.
代价函数J的cμ
This cost function is sometimes
这个代价函数
also called the distortion cost
在K均值算法中
function or the distortion of
有时候也叫做
the K-means algorithm.
失真代价函数(distortion cost function)
And, just to provide a little bit more
再解释详细点
detail, here's the K-means algorithm,
这是K均值算法
Here's exactly the algorithm as we have it, in the real
这跟我们之前得到的
form the earlier slide.
算法是一样的
And what this first step
这个算法的第一步
of this algorithm is, this was
就是聚类中心的分配
the cluster assignment step
在这一步中
where we assign each
我们要把每一个点
point to the cluster centroid, and
划分给各自所属的聚类中心
it's possible to show mathematically that
可以用数学证明
what the cluster assignment step
这个聚类簇的划分步骤
is doing is exactly minimizing
实际上就是在
J with respect
对代价函数 J 进行最小化
to the variables, C1, C2
关于参数 c(1) c(2)
and so on, up
等等
to C(m), while holding the
一直到 c(m)
closest centroids, MU1 up to
而保持最近的聚类中心 μ1
MUK fixed.
到 μk 固定不变
So, what the first assignment step
因此 第一步要做的
does is you know, it doesn't change
其实不是改变
the cluster centroids, but what it's
聚类中心的位置
doing is, exactly picking the values of C1, C2, up to CM
而是选择 c(1) c(2) 一直到 c(m)
that minimizes the cost
来最小化这个代价函数
function or the distortion function,
或者说失真函数 J
J. And it's possible to prove
不难从数学的角度证明
that mathematically but, I won't do so here.
但我在这里就不做了
That has a pretty intuitive meaning
有一个很直观的意义，
of just, yo know, well let's assign
只是，你知道的，那么让我们将
these points to the cluster centroid
这些点到聚类中心
that is closest to it, because
使之最接近它，因为
that's what minimizes the square
这是最小平方距离的点
of distance between the points and the corresponding cluster centroid.
和相应的聚类中心之间。
And then the other part of
然后
the second step of K-means, this second step over here.
K-均值算法的第二步
This second step was the move
第二步是再次移动
centroid step and,
中心点的步骤,
once again, I won't prove it,
我不会去证明，
but it can be shown
但它可以
mathematically, that what the
用数学方法显示, 求中心
root centroid step does, is
点步骤做的是，
it chooses the values
选择
of mu that minimizes J.
最小化mu得到的值
So it minimizes the cost function J with respect to,
因此它的对J代价函数最小化，
where wrt is my
用wrt
abbreviation for with respect to.
作为缩写
But it minimizes J with respect
但它最小化J
to the locations of the cluster centroids, Mu1 through MuK.
与聚类中心的位置，从Mu1 到 MuK.
So, what K-means really
所以， K均值方法真正
is doing is it's taking the
做的是，它采用
two sets of variables and
两组变量并
partitioning them into two halves right here.
把它们分成两半。
First the C set of variables and then you have the Mu sets of variables.
C组变量和Mu组变量。
And what it does is it first
其做法是
minimizes J with respect
最小化J与
to the variable C, and then minimizes
变量c，接着最小化
J with respect the variables
与变量
Mu, and then it keeps on iterating.
Mu，接着保持迭代。
And so that's all that K-means does.
所以，这就是K均值所做的。
And, now that we understand
而且，现在我们明白
K-means, let's try to
k-均值，让我们尽量
minimize this cost function J.  We
减少这种代价函数J.
我们
can also use this to
还可以用这个
try to debug our learning
来调试我们的学习
algorithm and just kind
算法，就是
of make sure that our implementation
确保我们实现
of K-means is running correctly.
k-均值正确运行。
So, we now understand the
所以，我们理解
K-means algorithm as trying to
K-均值算法来
optimize this cost function J,
优化代价函数J，
which is also called the dispulsion function.
它也被叫做 dispulsion 函数。
We can use that to debug K-means
我们可以用它来调试k-均值
and help me show that K-means
帮我表明k-均值是
is converging, and that it's
收敛的，而且它
running properly, and in the
正常运行，在
next video, we'll also see
下一个视频中, 我们也可以看到
how we can us this to
我们怎样用这个方法
help K-means find better clusters
帮助K均值找到更好的簇
and help K-means to avoid local optima.
并帮助k均值避免局部最优解。